刑法により禁じられた犯罪行為＞
＜５年以下の懲役 または➡
50万円以下の
罰金に処せられます＞
＜後悔しても 元には戻せない＞
不正視聴!?
The Tale of Jiraiya the Gallant
(綱手)嫌な雨が続くな。
There's no end to this awful rain...
((自来也 : アハハハッ 冗談だ 冗談！
Joking! I'm just joking!
(お前には感謝してる))
You know, I'm grateful to you.
(シズネ)自来也様なら大丈夫です。
あの方がそうそう…。
I'm sure Master Jiraiya is fine.
He, of all people, wouldn't...
He's not coming back...
アイツは帰って来ない。
えっ…。
Huh?
私はそっちに賭けた。
That's what I bet him.
私の賭けは 必ずハズれるからな。
And I never win my bets.
そういうことですか。
Oh, I see.
((自来也 : 男はフラれて強くなる。
Rejection makes a man stronger.
(それに 幸せなんてのは
男が求めるもんじゃないのぉ))
And besides...
men aren't the ones
who seek happiness.
フッ かっこつけやがって。
What a poser...
帰って来たら そろそろ
かっこつかなくさせてやるかな。
When he gets back...
I won't let him keep his cool.
ペイン お前はいったい何者なんだ。
Pain... What are you?!
(ペイン)ペイン それはオレたち
６人全員を指し示す呼び名だ。
Pain...
That name is an alias that
denotes all six of us.
Y-You're...!
お お前は その顔…。
That face...
弥彦なのか？
Is that you, Yahiko?
Oh yeah... There was such a guy,
wasn't there?
((ああ いたな そんなヤツも。
とっくに死んだよ そんなヤツは))
He died a long time ago.
What's going on?
I thought you said Yahiko died!
いったい どういうことだ？
弥彦は死んだんじゃ…。
Plus, those eyes...
それにその目…。
You see Yahiko's image in me?
オレに弥彦の面影を見たか。
やはりかつての師ではある。
You really are his former Teacher.
だが すでに弥彦は死んだ。
But Yahiko has been dead
for quite some time.
ここにいるのは ペインだ。
All that remains...is Pain.
そんな屁理屈はいい！
なぜお前が輪廻眼を持っている！
Quit it with the wordplay!
Why do you possess the Rinnegan?!
What are you talking about,
Jiraiya-boy?
(フカサク)
どういうことじゃ 自来也ちゃん。
かつての
弟子の１人があのなかにいます。
One of my former students
is among them.
Except he didn't use to
possess those eyes...
ただその子は
あの目を持ってはいなかった。
(シマ)いったい 何が
どうなっとるんじゃ？
What in tarnation is going on?
あのなかに
予言の子が２人もおるんか？
You saying there are
two children of prophecy?
《いや 違う。 輪廻眼を見て➡
No, that's not it either...
When I saw the Rinnegan, I convinced
myself that the first one was Nagato...
最初のヤツを
長門だと思い込んでしまったが➡
わしが知る長門とは違和感がある。
But he's subtly different
from the Nagato I knew of...
それによく見れば
あの６人のなかに➡
Come to think of it,
upon closer inspection,
none of those six remind me of Nagato.
長門の面影を感じるヤツは
１人としていない。
On the other hand,
one of them resembles Yahiko...
それなのに 弥彦の面影を持ち➡
長門の輪廻眼を持つものがいる》
but possesses Nagato's Rinnegan...
弥彦なのか 長門なのか…。
Are you Yahiko...or Nagato?
お前らは いったい何なんだ？
Just what exactly are you?!
我々は ペイン。
We are Pain...
神だ。
We are god.
自来也ちゃん 退け！
Retreat, Jiraiya-boy!
A god?!
《神だと？》
弥彦 なぜお前が
長門の目を持っている？
Yahiko! How could you possess
Nagato's eyes?!
そんなことを知っても
我々には勝てん！
Even if you knew that,
you could not win!
小僧！ あきらめんさい！
Lad! Give up already!
I must find an opening to defeat them,
even if it kills me!
なんとか 隙を見つけて
刺し違えてでも…。
気配が消えた。
I don't sense his presence...
ここは… 結界か…。
This is...a barrier?
《胃液？》
Gastric fluid?
Rasengan!
螺旋丸！
やったのぉ 自来也ちゃん。
You did it, Jiraiya-boy.
(シマ)死んだか…。
Is he dead?
I barely managed to kill one...
(自来也)結界に引きずり込んで
やっとで 一人か…。
only after dragging it into my barrier...
大丈夫か!? 小僧！
くっ… なんとか…。
Are you all right, lad?
Somewhat...
My body...?!
体が… チャクラが乱される！
My chakra's agitated!
これか!?
Is it this?!
正体も奇妙じゃけどの 武器まで
奇妙なものを使うてくるわい。
Their identity is a mystery,
and they seem to use odd weapons too.
コイツらはもう
ただの人じゃあらへんの。
They're no longer mortals...
They're something entirely different.
何か 別のものじゃ。
((誰も 彼の顔を
よく知らないし➡
No one really knows what
he looks like.
実際には
存在しないんじゃないか と➡
And some claim that
he doesn't even exist.
(ウワサする者さえいる))
《自来也 : あの顔…
ヤツは 間違いなく 弥彦だ》
That face...
He is unmistakably Yahiko...
《それなのに
長門の輪廻眼を持っていた。
And yet,
he possesses Nagato's Rinnegan...
弥彦が なんらかの理由で
長門から奪い取ったのか？
Did Yahiko steal them
from Nagato for some reason?
しかし… 他にも
あれだけの輪廻眼がある。
But...
There are other
Rinnegan bearers as well...
いったい どういうことだ…》
So what's going on?
Plus...
《それに…》
Understanding such pain enables you
to be kind to others...
((自来也 : だが そういう痛みを
知っているからこそ➡
人に優しくできることもある。
それが 人だ。
That's what makes us human.
(長門)それって… どういうこと？
What do you mean by that...?
成長するってことだのぉ。
It's called growing up.
(長門)成長するって…
つまり どういうこと？
Growing up? What do you mean?
(自来也)どうするか
自分で考えることだ))
That, you need to figure out yourself.
((ここでは人が死にすぎる。
Too many people die here.
That pain made me grow up.
(それらの痛みが オレを成長させた))
だとすると
やはりコイツが長門か…。
In which case,
does that mean he is Nagato?
んっ!?
そうだ 思い出した！
That's right! Now I remember!
This one is definitely not Nagato!
コイツは 長門なんかじゃない！
どうした!?
この目の前の男➡
What's the matter?
This fellow before us...
前に一度
手合わせしたことがある。
I've fought him before.
大ガマ仙人の予言に従って
旅を始めたばかりの頃 出会った➡
He was a Fuma Clan member
I encountered
right after setting out on my journey,
following the Great Lord Elder's prophecy.
風魔一族の男だ。
この額の傷は わしがつけたもの。
I gave him that scar on his forehead...
So what's a fellow like him
doing here?
なんで そんなヤツが
ここにおるんなら？
Now I'm even more confused
about this whole Pain mystery.
ますます ペインのことが
わからんようになったな。
((大ガマ仙人 : おぬしは
その変革者を導く者じゃ。
You will guide that revolutionary.
The day will come when you will be
forced to make a critical selection.
いずれ おぬしには大きな選択を
迫られるときが来るじゃろう。
わしは
どうすればいいんですか？
What must I do...?
正しく選択するには！
In order to make the right choice?
In my dream, you traveled the world,
writing books.
(夢では 世界を歩いて
本を書いておったのう))
《まさか 予言のとおりなら…》
It can't be...
If this is the prophecy...
わしは もう一度 ヤツらの前に出て
確かめたいことがあります。
I wish to go back and face them
in order to confirm something...
You two please go back.
お二人は お帰りください。
What?!
なに!?
ダメじゃ！
Absolutely not! You will be killed
if you go out again!
次 出ていけば必ず殺される。
さらに眼が増えた。
They have more eyes,
それに結界トラップが二度も通じる
相手じゃありゃせんぞ！
and they will not fall
for the barrier trap twice!
They're not on to us in here yet.
今 ヤツらは
こっちに気づいとらんのじゃけん。
逃げるなら今しかない！
This is our only chance to
make a run for it!
今 出て行けば
殺されるかもしれませんがの。
I may be killed if I go out there...
だが 敵の正体を
つかめるかもしれません。
But I may be able to learn
the truth about them.
この機を逃したら➡
If I let this chance slip by,
I don't think there's anyone else
who could get as close to Pain.
もう ここまでペインに近づける者は
たぶん おらんでしょう。
This is our only chance to
uncover the truth...
正体を見抜くチャンスは 今しかない！
そして… 今こそが
大ガマ仙人の予言された➡
Plus...
This is the time for selection
that the Great Lord Elder prophesied!
選択のとき！
Boss and Ma'am...
頭と姐さんは
今までのペインの情報と➡
please take the intel on Pain
we've gathered so far,
as well as this corpse and go back.
このペインの死体を
持って帰ってくだされ。
そして 綱手に…。
And please tell Tsunade...
それは
かあちゃんだけで十分じゃ。
Ma should be enough for that.
えっ!? しかし！
But...
Just return by dinnertime.
晩飯までに戻りんさい。
ああ 終わったら
自来也ちゃんと一緒に➡
Yup... When we're done here,
I'll bring Jiraiya-boy on over with me.
飯を食いに帰る。
《ありがとう… ございます》
Thank you...
It's just as I thought!
《やっぱり そうだ！》
《コイツら全員
わしの会ったことのある忍だ》
They're all ninjas that
I've encountered before!
《そうか わかったぞ ペインの正体》
That's it!
I've figured out who Pain is!
My throat...
《ノドが…！》
自来也ちゃん！
Jiraiya-boy!
遅かったな気づくのが。
You were too late in figuring it out...
《ペインの正体
頭に伝えなくては…》
I must let Boss know...about
Pain's true identity.
しっかりしろ 自来也ちゃん！
Hang in there, Jiraiya-boy!
《ダメだ… ノドを潰されたか。
It's no good...
My throat has been crushed.
クソッ！ これでは…。
Damn it... At this rate...
ダメだ… 気が遠くなる。
It's useless... I'm passing out...
わしは… 死ぬのか？
Am I...going to die?
失敗なのか？》
Have I failed...?
《自来也 : 忍は生きざまではなく
死にざまの世界…。
It's not how you live,
but how you die in
the ninja world...
忍の人生とはどうやって
生きてきたかではなく➡
A ninja's life is not measured
by how they lived
死ぬまでに何をしたかで
その価値が決まる。
but rather what they managed
to accomplish before their death.
思い返せば
わしの人生は失敗ばかりだった。
Looking back, my life has
been nothing but failures...
綱手にフラれ続け
友を止めることもできず➡
Continually rejected by Tsunade...
Unable to stop my friend...
弟子と師を
守ることもできなかった。
And unable to protect either
my student or my mentor...
火影たちが成した偉業に
比べれば わしのしてきたことは➡
Compared to the great deeds
of the Hokage,
my actions are trifling,
insignificant things indeed.
取るに足らぬ
くだらぬことばかり…。
わしも 歴代火影たちのように
死にたかった。
I wish I could have died like
each of the Hokage.
物語は最後の結びのできで決まる。
A tale is only good as
its final turn of events, the plot twist.
失敗も一興！ その試練が 己を
磨いてくれたと信じ 生きてきた。
Failures must be seen
as mere amusements!
They are trials, which hone your skills.
I lived believing that...
And in return, I swore I would
accomplish a deed so great
その代わり 今までの失敗を
チャラにするような➡
that it would obliterate all
of my failures...
大きな偉業をなし遂げ
立派な忍として死ぬ。
And I'd die a splendid ninja!
At least, that's how it
was supposed to go...
そのはずだった。 フフフ…。
But...with my plot twist...
だが その結び…
死にざまがこれか。
My tale, ending like this...
大ガマ仙人は わしを
変革者を導く者と予言した。
The Great Lord Elder prophesied that
I would guide that revolutionary.
A person who will make
a great choice
忍の世界の安定と破壊に関わる
大きな選択をする者 と。
that will bring either stability
or destruction to the ninja world.
ここで ペインを倒し 暁を止め
忍の世界を救う…。
I thought I would defeat Pain,
stop the Akatsuki,
and save the ninja world
from destruction...
But in the end, I failed in
that selection too.
結局 その選択も
失敗してしまった。
How pitiful...
情けないのぉ…。
that this will be the twist to
"The Tale of Jiraiya the Gallant."
これが 自来也豪傑物語の
結びだとはのぉ…。
くだらぬ物語だった》
What a worthless story...
((ミナト : いいや
そんなことはないです。
No, I don't think so.
This tale is wonderful!
この物語は すばらしいです。
エピソードが 先生の数々の伝説に
なぞらえてあって➡
Each chapter reads like one of
your numerous legendary exploits.
It's almost like an autobiography.
何か 自伝小説っぽくて…。
この本の主人公… 最後まで➡
The main character of this book...
I thought his determination to
never give up was really cool...
あきらめなかったところが
かっこよかった。
先生らしいですね この主人公。
He's a lot like you, Sensei.
そ… そうかのぉ？
Y-You think so...?
So I was thinking.
で… オレ 思ったんです。
ん？
Huh?
今度 生まれてくる子供も➡
I really hope my unborn child
こんな主人公みたいな忍に
なってくれたらいいな って。
can become a ninja just
like this main character!
だから この小説の主人公の名前
いただいてもいいですか？
Which is why I'd like your permission
to name my son after him.
H-Hey! Are you sure?
お… おい！
そんなんで いいのか？
It's just a random name that
I thought up while eating ramen.
ラーメン 食いながら
適当に決めた名前だぞ。
Naruto...
(クシナ)ナルト…。
ステキな名前です。
It's a wonderful name.
クシナ…。
Kushina...
アハハハ… ったく… ってことは
わしが名づけ親かのぉ？
Cripes...
So that makes me his godfather?
わしなんかで 本当にいいのか？
Are you really sure about this?
先生だからこそです。
You are my sensei!
本当の忍の才能を持つ
立派な忍者で➡
And you are a great ninja who possesses
the true talent of a ninja!
There's no other like you.
(あなたほどの忍は
いませんからね))
Yes...
《そうだ… そうだった。
わしは あの子に…》
That's right...
I gave that child...
((ナルト : オレってば 火影になる!!
I'm gonna become the Hokage!
A Hokage that surpasses
all previous Hokage!
そんでもって どの火影をも超える
火影になるんだ！
I never go back on my word...
That's my ninja way!
(まっすぐ 自分の言葉は曲げねえ。
それが オレの忍道だ！))
《ナルト… 思えば お前は
あの小説の主人公どおりだ。
Naruto...
Now that I think about it, Naruto,
you are just like that
novel's main character.
ミナトとクシナの想い… 願いを
ちゃんと受け取っていた。
You've inherited Minato and
Kushina's wishes, their hopes...
それなのに わしは…》
And yet...I...
((先生だからこそです。
You are my sensei!
本当の忍の才能を持つ
立派な忍者で➡
And you are a great ninja who
possesses the true talent of a ninja!
There's no other like you.
(あなたほどの忍は
いませんからね))
((忍者とは
忍び堪える者のことなんだよ。
A ninja is one who endures,
one who stands brave.
ひとつ テメエに教えといてやる。
Let me teach you one thing...
The most important attribute
of a ninja
忍の才能で いちばん大切なのは
持っている術の数なんかじゃねえ。
is not the number of jutsu he masters.
(大切なのは
あきらめねえ ド根性だ！))
《まっすぐ
自分の言葉は曲げない。
そして どんなときも
あきらめない。
それが お前の忍道なら…
ナルトよ！ わしは そのお前の師だ。
弱音を吐くわけにはいかんのぉ。
なぜなら 弟子の忍道は
師匠ゆずりと相場は決まっとる。
なぁ そうだろ？ ナルトよ。 のぉ!!》
《気力で吹き返したんか!?》
自来也ちゃん！
心の臓は止まっていたはずだが…。
よし！
くっ…。
《あきらめねえ…。
それこそが わしの取るべき
本当の選択だった！》
さすがに しぶといな。
片づける。
よし！ 確かに受け取ったけんの!!
ダイイングメッセージ… 暗号化したか。
《ナルト… 予言の子は
間違いなくお前だ。
あとは… すべて託すぞ…》
カエルには逃げられたか…。
《自来也豪傑物語…。
これで ちったぁ
マシになったかのぉ…。
最終章… 井の中の蛙
大海で散る… の巻か。
フフフ… ほどほどに
あっぱれ あっぱれ…。
さて… そろそろ
ペンを置くとしよう。
おお… そうだ！
続編のタイトルは 何がいいかのぉ。
そうだのぉ…。
『うずまきナルト物語』
うむ… それが いい…》
《ウルティア : 許せない… 許せない…》
私は 煉獄の七眷属が長
ウルティア！
(グレイ)こいよ 不良娘！
母親に代わって
説教してやらぁ！